# 哈喽大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 今天我把我起的那一锅卤水拿回来
I brought back the pot of master stock I made yesterday.
# 然后买了一点这个鸭头
And then I bought some duck heads.
# 鸭脚 鸡脚 还有这个鸭翅
Duck feet, chicken feet, and duck wings.
# 卤一锅卤货给我四伯爷吃一下
Let's cook a pot of Luwei (master stock braised food) for Uncle.
# 我把它卤耙点嘛
I'll braise them a bit softer.
# 不卤耙我就咬不动
I can't bite if they are not soft.
# 你卤耙了我多吃得到几个
I can eat more if you braise them soft enough.
# 要的啊
Yes.
# 把这个鸡脚脚趾给它剪一下
Cut off the toes of the chicken feet.
# 鸭脚 这个鸭脚趾一起剪了
Also for the duck feet.
# 好啦 现在已经剪得差不多了 然后我准备卤了
Well, now it's basically done, I'm going to make it.
# 卤之前先焯一下水
Parboil them before braising.
# 要得了
Good
# 整了好多哦
That's a lot.
# 先倒下去焯哈水
Pour them down and parboil them first.
# 这点多啊 这点不多
That's a lot? That's not much.
# 你猜这锅水烧得到好久（烧开）
Guess how long it takes to boil this much water?
# 十分钟
Ten minutes
# 我给你说四分钟
I think it's about four minutes.
# 三分钟都可以烧得开
Maybe in three minutes.
# 等会这个卤好了给邻居都尝哈
When it's ready, let the neighbors try it.
# 要的
Yes.
# 到时候分享给大家尝一下
Let's share it with them.
# 这个卤出来很香
This will be so good.
# 这个是血沫的嘛 四伯爷
This is blood scum, Uncle.
# 血沫
Scum
# 好 差不多要得了
Okay, almost there.
# 这就煮好了啊
It's already cooked?
# 不是煮好 这是焯水安
It's not cooked. It's only parboiled.
# 还是不少噶 你看
There's still a lot of them, see?
# 放它上来 放上来
Put it up. Put it up.
# 放上去啊
Put it up?
# 嗯放上去
Yeah, put it on there.
# 哦 拿这个来烧啊
Oh, braise them with this.
# 好重
So heavy
# 这次卤得不是很多 只有十多斤
Not too much this time, only ten Jin (5kg).
# 吃的人多嘛
There's a lot of people eating.
# 肯定哦
Sure.
# 我们这一般卤个40分钟的话 就刚好适合年轻人的口感
We usually braise it for 40 minutes, and it's just right for young people's taste.
# 如果像我伯爷这种老年人吃的话最好卤够50分钟
If an old man like my uncle eats it, better cook it for 50 minutes.
# 然后再泡它20分钟就可以了
Then soak it for another 20 minutes and that's it.
# 烫哦
Hot.
# 嗯 还差一点香味 再加点香料
Yeah, it still needs more fragrance. Some more spices.
# 然后再加点糖
Then add more sugar.
# 再加点盐给它把味道调一下
Add some salt to flavor it.
# 因为这个卤水的话要稍微咸一点
Because the master stock need to be a bit saltier.
# 它卤出来的东西才够味
So the Luwei's taste could be better.
# 如果说你这个卤水刚好够味的话
If the master stock tastes just about right.
# 卤出来的东西它那个泡的时间不够的话
The Luwei couldn't taste that good unless it had enough time to soak.
# 吃起来味道就始终差一点
The taste is not as good.
# 好 现在我们加点这个花椒辣椒香料
Okay, now we're gonna add the Sichuan peppercorns, chili and spices.
# 因为是刚开始卤的话
It's because I've just started the master stock.
# 这个要稍微多一点点
So I need to add a bit more spice.
# 这个的话我们是用清水泡过的
They are already soaked in clean water.
# 如果是商业版用的话用白酒泡
If it's for commercial use, soak them in Baijiu.
# 白酒可以反复用来使用
Baijiu can be used over and over again
# 现在我们再加一点这个盐 还有这个冰糖
Let's add a little more salt and rock sugar.
# 给它调一下味
Adjust its taste.
# 现在就是保持让它开的状态卤够40分钟
Now just keep it on for 40 minutes.
# 卤50分钟嘛
I will say 50 minutes for uncle.
# 这个卤水啊 熬卤水的那个老母鸡越老越好
This master stock... the older the hen, the better.
# 香都嘛
Yes
# 好啦 现在我们要慢慢等了
All right, now we're going to wait.
# 走嘛 过去坐着慢慢等
Let's go sit and wait.
# 用六七年的老母鸡
If you use six or seven years old hens for the stock, that will be amazing.
# 就这样等它开着就行了
Just wait for it to braise.
# 走嘛 我们坐着慢慢等
Come on, let's sit and wait.
# 好了 现在我们这个已经卤了有40多分钟
Okay, now it's already braised for over 40 minutes.
# 也泡了20分钟了 现在把它捞出来
It's also soaked for 20 minutes, too. Now let's get them out.
# 但是那个鸭头的话就还要再泡一会儿
The duck heads will take a little longer to soak.
# 把这个卤好的拿出来
Take them out of the master stock.
# 这个鸡脚禁不起卤 已经耙了
This chicken feet can't braise too long. It's already soft.
# 来 四伯爷尝哈看
Come on, Uncle, have a taste.
# 我啃一个脚爪看耙没耙都
Let me try a chicken feet to see if I can bite it.
# 这种都煮烂了 这种都感觉要开始烂了
It's soft. It feels like it's starting to melt.
# 这个卤货要等到它稍微凉一点了
This Luwei need to wait until it's a little cooler.
# 那个味道才能收得进去
The flavor can get into the meat more.
# 热的时候
When it's hot...
# 这个凉菜就是要冷了才好吃撒
It's a cold dish. It's supposed to be better eaten cold.
# 热的时候没得那么好吃的
When it's hot, it still doesn't reach its best.
# 伯娘
Aunt
# 嗯 还可以
Yeah, it's good.
# 来嘛 尝哈看
Come on, try it.
# 卤耙了的
Soft
# 耙了的
Soft is good
# 我都啃得动 你还啃不动啊
Even I can bite it, you must also can.
# 嗯 耙了的
Yeah, it was soft.
# 第一次这个花椒有点重
The Sichuan peppercorn flavor is very strong since this is the first time stock.
# 多卤几次的话 这个花椒就更香了
The Sichuan peppercorn will be more fragrant if you use the stock more.
# 街上卖的硬的我啃都啃不动
I can't even bite the tough Luwei they sell on the street.
# 嗯 我也觉得这个鸭（鸡）脚可以 找一个硬一点的
Yeah, the duck foot feels good. Let me find a tougher one.
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里
All right, that's it for this video.
# 如果你们想尝试一下这个
If you want to try this.
# 可以缩小一下它的比例 家里也可以做
We can scale it down. You can also do it at home. (Refer to the previous video)
# 街上卖的很绵
The ones sold on the street are too tough.
# 有点绵噶
It's a bit of too hard for old man.
# 嗯 这卤得完全都脱骨了
Yeah, today's Luwei are off the bone soft.